KAMAL OLAGUNJU

Email: okamaldeen@gmail.com | Phone: +1 (647) 887 1501

I am a Certified Supply Chain Management Professional (CSCMP) with over 5 years' experience spanning across the construction, manufacturing, SaaS and financial services industry across four continents focusing on business process improvement, project management, integrated business planning and customer experience/success. I have been able to forge partnerships that help in accomplishing the goals of clients. Using CRM, I am able to analyze and use historical data to provide insights and delineate factors that influence customer behavior. My persuasive communication skills strengthen my ability to empathize with clients across multiple touch points and ensure positive customer journeys. My focus is on continuously adapting and honing my skills to meet the objectives of any organization I work with.

SKILLS

- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook), Visio, MS Project, Dynamics CRM, SharePoint OBIEE
- Knowledge of business process design, process improvement methodology, Six Sigma and Kaizen
- Data Analysis, Customer Journey Mapping, Project Management, Negotiation, Presentation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Descartes Visual Compliance, Toronto

Sep 2020 - Nov 2020

Customer Success

- Reviewed historical customer data and provided insights to stakeholders to aid improvement of product offering
- Secured commitments for product subscription and contract renewals based on risk and usage analysis
- Liaised with customer service and other internal teams to discuss annual forecasts and resolve customer issues

FirstBank Nov 2017 - Jan 2020

Segment Management & Customer Experience

FirstBank is a leading financial services institution and a premier commercial bank with over 750 business location across 10 countries with a market capitalization of \$650 million and \$21 billion in asset holdings

- Analyzed forecasts predicting customer spending patterns, leveraging data analytics and CRM to provide insights
- Resolved complaints by identifying, documenting, investigating issues, researching, exploring solutions and drawing out resolution implementation roadmaps. Oversaw the implementation of recommended solutions
- Ensured change projects were planned, managed effectively and adequately rolled out to ensure adoption and sustainability of new systems and business processes by staff and clients respectively
- Maintained relationships with customers, project managers, decision makers and executive sponsors at multiple touch points throughout the customer lifecycle
- Coordinated voice of customer (VOC) sessions, focus groups and analysed complaint trends to identify root causes
 of service delivery gaps, benchmarked and ensured process and technology improvements and corrective actions
- Drafted monthly presentations and reports to management on the progress of initiatives and followed up with crossfunctional teams on implementation of initiatives that enhanced operational efficiencies and process enhancements
- Conducted ATM cash demand forecasts using customer analytics and trend analysis to inform replenishment plans
- Administered surveys through questionnaires, focus group sessions and interviews using Qualtrics to analyse feedback that aided in decision making at the organizational level as well as recommendations to management
- Mapped activities related to business process analysis and improvement including key performance metrics, redundant processes and performed gap analysis to evaluate current and future change requirement processes
- Drove initiatives across people, process and technology pillars across the bank and ensured effective change management by conducting change impact assessments which aided in mitigating against risks and losses
- Updated and maintained departmental Standard Operating Procedures (SOP), ensured compliance with Operational Risk Processes and Business Continuity Plans (BCP) in accordance with ISO27001 and ISO22301

Al Nafees-Renent (General Construction), Dubai

Jan 2014 - Oct 2017

Customer Relations & Business Development

Al Nafees-Renent is a property facility management agent for a portfolio of blue-chip corporate and industrial properties

- Analyzed information workflows and collaborated with the operations team to implement a process improvement strategy that reduced operational expenditures by 40% and enhanced quality of on-time service delivery
- Coordinated business project delivery on time and on budget by identifying project bottlenecks, utilizing project management methodologies that ensured adherence to high quality standards whilst meeting needs of clients
- Maintained adequate resourcing of supply inputs and tools used on the numerous construction sites
- Implemented new business initiatives by evaluating and changing existing business processes and procedures
- Responded to RFI's and RFQ's and negotiated with suppliers to improve cost savings for purchasing of materials and supplies
- Built and leveraged collaborative relationships with clients and other business partners to identify improvement
 opportunities, service gaps and developed solutions to rectify any issues
- Analyzed operational performance levels and supervised functions to ensure adherence to environmental management standards and avoid under-utilization/misallocation of resources
- Assisted in the implementation of the budgeting and forecasting tool, adoption planning across the company
- Managed projects and implemented quality control procedures that led to stable processes and quality output

EDUCATION, QUALIFICATIONS & TRAINING	
University of Warwick, UK	2011-2012
MSc. Supply Chain and Logistics Management	
Loughborough University, UK	2008-2011
BSc. Economics with Accounting	
Bradford College, UK	2006-2008
A-Levels: Accounting, Business Studies, Sociology	
The Chartered Institute of Logistics and Transport	
Certified Supply Chain Management Professional (CSCMP)	2014
	2021
Strategic Planning Foundations (Linkedin Learning, PMI & NASBA)	
Financial Modeling and Forecasting Financial Statements (Linkedin Learning, NASBA)	2021
Customer Value Management, Lean Six Sigma & Customer Insights Training	2018
The Internet of things, FutureLearn (King's College London)	2017
Supply Chains in Practice: How Things Get to You, FutureLearn (University of Warwick)	2016